ABHISHEK. J.N

| Phone: +918660151380 | <u>abhishekwithu101@gmail.com</u> |

https://github.com/abhishek-netizen | https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-jn-3892928a/ |

Certified Data Scientist with 1.5 years of experience with a bachelor degree in electrical & electronics engineering. Seeking opportunities where I can utilize my analytical, mathematical and technical skills to solve real life problems related to analyzing a big volume of datasets to draw insights that can help with business decisions

Skills

Programming:

- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Dash, Beautifulsoup, NLTK, Keras, Tensorflow), &
- R, SQL, Selenium, MS-Excel

Visualization:

• Tableau, Excel Charts, Jupyter Notebook

Database:

MySQL

Areas of Expertise:

- 1. Linear Regression 2. Logistic Regression 3. Decisiontrees & Randomforest Xgboost
- 1.PCA 2. SVM 3. Clustering 4. KNN 5. AprioriAlgorithm 6. Neural-Net 7. NLP 8. Hyper parameter tuning
- 1. Time-series 2. Flask frame work for deployment 3. Docker Container 4. Heroku, Azure, Kubernetes
- 1. PySpark (RDD, PySpark SQL, PySpark Mlib) 2. Git

Courses

Fundamentals of Statistics Complete Web Development Bootcamp Data Analysis With Excel

Certifications

- Received professional Data Science and Machine Learning certification provided by Excel-R (Duration- 6months)
- Received a passing grade badge and certification in Deep Learning Using Tensorflow provided by IBM
- Received certification for successfully completing Python For Data Science from Educha
- Received certification for successfully completing Complete Web Development(HTML, CSS, Bottstrap, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS) provided by Udemy

Experience

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019

Smart Grid & Distribution Automation System Bescom , Bengaluru – *Project Engineer*

Ensure Proactive and Responsive Analysis of the Data of 11Kv Distribution Power Networks of Bangalore

- Collected real-time substations data from various region of the Bangalore using wire shark and auto classified the data based on various parameters
- Prepared various dashboards using Python-Dash for month on month Distribution Load Forecasting
- Evaluation and analysis of outage report using Excel V-lookup, Chi-square, Normal and T-distribution. Removed outliers using Python and Pandas
- Help organization to decide future loads of next month to forecasting on individual station loads to avoid overloading of the station and to ensure uninterrupted power supply using time-series analysis and Excel
- Worked on simple **Tableau** visualization for the purpose of presentations.

Internships

11 Jun 2020 – 17 Aug 2020

Innodatatics ,Bengaluru - Data Science Intern

- Data wrangling, Feature engineering, & Data visualization to get insights from the data doing EDA using Tableau, Python matplotlib and seaborn, R studio libraries
- Model building using various machine learning algorithms i.e. Supervised and Unsupervised algorithms
- Evaluation and analysis of insurance claims dataset using Excel V-lookup, Chi-square, Normal and T-distribution. Removed outliers using Python and Pandas
- Worked on scraping required data from various websites using Python BeautifulSoup,
 Selenium
- Worked on deployment of ml models using **Python Flask** framework on various cloud such as Heroku, Azure, & Kubernetes

03 Oct 2020 - 11 Nov 2020

Technolabs, Indore – *Machine Learning Developer*

- Worked on case study of various machine learning classification alogorithms
- Built and deployed the machine learning algorithm on cloud using python flask frame work
- Currently working on one of the deep learning project provided by the organization

31 Oct 2020 – 01 Dec 2020

The Spark Foundation, Singapore – Data Science and Business Analytics Intern

- Working on data wrangling, Data visualization, making insights reports
- Working on building business suitable machine learning models

Projects

Predicting E-Commerce Product Recommendation Ratings From Reviews

 Unstructured text data to analyze the dominant sentiments in various social documents and reviews forums using sentiment analysis, with the help of web scraping tools and API's

Technologies/Module used: Python(NPM-libraries), Scikit-learn, NLTK contractions

Flight Ticket Fare Analysis

 Built a machine learning algorithm to understand what factors will affects the price of the airfare and successfully able to predict the patterns. <u>click here</u> to view deployment **Technologies/Module** used: Python(NPM-libraries), Sklearn, Time-series and LSTM

Credit Card Default Prediction

 Built a machine learning algorithm to predict if the client is going to be default or Not based on the previous moth survey conducted by the bank. <u>cleck here</u> to view deployment

Technologies/Module used: Python(NPM-libraries), Sklearn, Logistic-regression, Decision trees, Random forest, Cross Validation

Other Activities

- Participated in analytics vidya blogathon to write a blog on data science topics
- Completed **KPMG data science virtual internship** program

Education

Jul 2015 - August 2018

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belagavi - Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronic specialization from Acharya Institute of Technology, Bengaluru

7.1 CGPA